Savannah Hammerton

GRADUATE STUDENT, EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS

University of Georgia College of Public Health

□ 423 544 2453 | Savannah.hammerton@uga.edu | Osmhammerton | osmhammerton

About

Graduate student working towards MS in Epidemiology & Biostatistics (concentration in Epidemiology) and Graduate Certificate in Infectious Disease Epidemiology. Particular interest and research emphasis in infectious diseases, infectious disease dynamics, and One Health. Past experience in healthcare, providing strong contextual understanding of disease determinants, prevention, treatment, and outcomes, as well as an understanding of the real world implications of public health research and practice on individuals. This experience also drives context-aware data analytic approaches to answering epidemiological questions. Passionate and driven to learn as much as possible in order to become an effective epidemiologist, with the goal of building a career that benefits others.

Education

University of Georgia (Current)

MS EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS | GRADUATE CERTIFICATE IN INFECTIOUS DISEASE EPIDEMIOLOGY

Columbus State University

BS, HEALTH SCIENCE

Chattanooga College
DIPLOMA, PRACTICAL NURSING (SUMMA CUM LAUDE, DIRECTOR'S AWARD FOR CONSISTENT ACADEMIC AND CLINICAL

EXCELLENCE)

Athens, GA

2020-2022

Columbus, GA

2018-2020

Chattanooga, TN

2014-2015

Relevant Experience _____

University of Georgia, Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics

GRADUATE ASSISANT (CURRENT)

Athens, GA 2021-2022

 Assist in administrative departmental tasks, faculty retreats/meeting planning, and department event planning. Create and maintain spreadsheets on department classes, students, etc. Develop presentation materials and assist in orientation. Generate documents with information on degree programs, Graduate School processes, etc. Participated in research with Dr. Jose Cordero, planning and implementing a systematic reivew of environmental exposures and preterm birth

ILoveKickboxing Columbus, GA

INSTUCTOR, ASSISTANT MANAGER

2018-2019

• Promoted to assistant manager after 9 months of employment. Responsible for personal health promotion and education for members, instructing group fitness classes, data management. with membership and point-of-sale systems. Integral part in data transfer when changing systems.

Georgetown Behavioral Health Institute

Georgetown, TX

LICENSED VOCATIONAL NURSE

2016-2016

• LVN working on adolescent male and female units, military unit. Conducted medication administration, milieu management, conflict resolution, patient chart management. Responsible for verbal de-escalation of agitated patients, medical complication and event management. Aided in coordination of care between all health care providers.

Encompass Home Health Pediatrics

Temple, TX

LICENSED VOCATIONAL NURSE

2016-2016

• Provided pediatric patient care for those needing 24-hour care or on hospice. Responsible for nutrition, hygiene, infection control, medication administration, respiratory status maintenance. Provided support to families of patients and socialization to patients throughout shifts.

Research.

NOVEMBER 2021

Antibody levels and disease outcomes in a norovirus challenge study (In Progress)

MS Thesis Project, Advisor - Dr. Andreas Handel

University of Georgia 2021

Preterm birth and environmental exposures: Systematic review (In Progress)

Research Assisantship, Dr. Jose

Cordero 2021

2019

University of Georgia

Prenatal exposure to flame retardants and adverse pregnancy outcomes: A systematic review (In Progress)

Contributor, Co-Author

University of Georgia 202.

Certifications _____

Social and Behavioral Research	
CITI PROGRAM	2021
Epidemics - The Dynamics of Infectious Diseases	
Coursera	2020
Certificate in Infectious Diseases and Disease Control	
Allegra Learning Solutions	2020
Essentials of Public Health Research	
CITI PROGRAM	2019
Research Involving Human Subjects	

Skills

CITI PROGRAM

Data Analysis

Primary coding language: R | Additional experience in: SAS, Stata, SPSS

Literature Searches and Management

ENDNOTE, ENDNOTE CLICK, ZOTERO

Laboratory Biosafety Level 2 Practices

EXPERIENCE IN SAFE MICROBIOLOGY LABORATORY PRACTICES WHEN WORKING WITH HUMAN PATHOGENS

Infectious Disease Modeling

Understanding of infectious disease modeling concepts, and experience in fitting infectious disease models

Organization

Skilled in managing multiple tasks and projects, maintaining high quality of work

Communication

PARTICIPATED IN CLINICAL, RESEARCH, AND PRIVATE GROUPS REQUIRING LARGE AMOUNTS OF COMMUNICATION AND COLLABORATION, BUILDING EXPERIENCE IN HEALTHY AND EFFICIENT COMMUNICATION SKILLS

Health Education

HAVE PROVIDED HEALTH EDUCATION IN BOTH CLINICAL AND NON-CLINICAL SETTINGS

Leadership/Management

EXPERIENCE IN MANAGEMENT, LEADERSHIP OF MULTIPLE EMPLOYEES

Organizations _____

Graduate Scholars of Epidemiology & Biostatistics (GSEB)

Secretary

2021-2021

Eta Sigma Gamma (ESG) | Health Science Honor Society

Member 2019-2020

American Public Health Association (APHA)

Member 2019-2021

Council of State and Territorial Epidemiologists (CSTE)

Member

2021-2021